[narrator] In the forest of the Dentora
region of the Republic of Padokea
lies a dormant volcano,
measuring 3,722 meters high.
It is known as Kukuroo Mountain.
It is home to a family
of famous assassins, The Zoldyck family.
Visitors arrive every day in hopes
of catching a glimpse of the mansion,
which has never been seen.
It's one of this nation's
most popular tourist attractions.
LAMENTATION TOURS
[theme song plays]
I have a message from Killua
that he asked me to relay to you.
"Thank you for coming.
I'm happy that you did.
But I can't see you right now.
I'm sorry."
THE X ZOLDYCK X FAMILY
[narrator] Gon, Kurapika and Leorio
have advanced a little closer
to their destination, The Zoldyck Mansion.
Meanwhile...
[Killua] I'm home.
[scoffs] Not like anyone's around.
[Illumi] Welcome back.
So, how did work go today?
Just fine.
Does that mean
you flawlessly dispatched your target?
Why ask? I'm sure you already know.
You were spying, right?
[Illumi chuckles]
Mom is waiting to talk to you inside.
-Don't wanna see her.
-I see.
[chuckles]
Huh?
[inhales, gasps]
Did you need something?
Oh, I wanted to say hello.
Are you new here?
I am. While you were away, I was hired on
as an apprentice butler, Master Killua.
My name is Canary.
-Oh, hey. You can have this.
-No, thanks.
But I do appreciate the gesture,
Master Killua.
You don't have to be so formal.
Just call me Killua.
I'm afraid I can't do that.
You are my employer,
and I am just a humble employee.
Wow. That's pretty stupid.
[chuckles]
[Killua] You were using the Silent Gait,
weren't you?
The Silent Gait?
The one where you move silently,
so you're completely undetectable.
In the Zoldyck family,
it's one of the first techniques
that we ever learn.
-Perfect for assassination.
-I didn't realize.
I suppose it's one of the many techniques
I learned
while I was growing up in Meteor City.
Meteor City?
Yes. That's where I was born.
A city that has been erased
from this world.
Huh? Well, never heard of it.
Where I come from,
you're allowed to dump anything there.
Which sort of explains
why so many members of the Mafia
and the Phantom Troupe come from there.
I'd like to see it one of these days.
When you do, I'd be happy to serve
as your guide. [chuckles]
[chuckles]
You know the Rhythm Echo?
-The Rhythm Echo? What is that?
-A technique using the Silent Gait.
[gasps]
If you just keep moving
at a particular rhythm,
it makes afterimages.
I see what you mean. Hm?
It seems we have intruders.
Quite a few of them, in fact.
Don't worry. Mike can handle it.
Mike is restrained today.
Those are the orders I was given.
They wish to test my abilities,
so I must comply.
Hmm...
We'll split up here
and keep searching the mountain
until we find their mansion. Huh?
Please leave, right now.
And just who the hell are you?
[Canary] Who I am is none of your concern.
You're trespassing on private property.
I can't allow you to pass
without permission.
Do you really think
a brat like you can stop us?
Look, you obviously don't stand a chance.
Stand aside and we'll spare your life.
How's that for a deal?
Take one step past this line,
and I'll remove you by force.
What was that?
Leave this one to us, boss.
No reason to get your hands dirty.
-Let's go!
-Yeah!
You messed with the wrong crew!
Huh.
[Seaquant yells]
[men grunting]
[groaning]
-Damn it!
-Get her!
[men yelling]
[grunting]
[men groaning]
[groaning]
-[boss grunts]
-[men groaning]
[weak groaning]
Do you wish to continue?
[boss] She took down all these grown men
without even breaking a sweat.
Are you a member of the Zoldyck family?
Certainly not.
I am merely an apprentice butler.
With your limited abilities,
you're not even a match for the butlers,
not to mention the Zoldyck family.
[boss] Grr!
[roaring]
How utterly meaningless.
[boss roars]
[boss grunts]
As I said, this is meaningless!
[grunts]
[roars]
[groans]
[gasps]
[Canary grunts]
[sneers] I'm a Hunter, kid,
and there's no way
I'm gonna lose to a little girl.
Hm.
[grunts]
[boss cackles] Prepare yourself, kid!
[gasps]
What?
[grumbles]
It's time to die! [grunting]
[boss screams]
[whimpers, yelps] I'm sorry!
Please don't kill me! I'm begging you!
Zebro.
-So you knew I was here, did you?
-Would you mind taking care of the rest?
Ah, of course.
Clean-up's my job, after all.
Besides, Mike is starving.
Huh? [screams]
No! Somebody help me, please!
[whimpers]
[chuckles]
-So, you knew Rhythm Echo already?
-Yes, I did.
I hope you'll forgive me.
Hmm. You think you're stronger than I am.
-Absolutely not.
-Oh, really?
I don't have any friends.
Will you be my friend, Canary?
[gasps]
I'm sorry, Master Killua. I honestly am.
[scoffs] That's so stupid.
[Gon] Let's be friends!
Gon.
HUNTER GLOSSARY
Hmm?
CANARY
Humph.
[Gon] Is she okay?
She's fine. She's just lost consciousness.
[growls] Wake up!
Oh. Hey, good morning, big bro.
What time is it?
[grunts] You arrogant little punk!
Arrogant? C'mon, look, I feel really awful
about stabbing you, big bro.
Sorry. I realize
I shouldn't have done that.
You liar! [grunting]
Can't fool you, huh?
-[growls] Tsk!
-[phone ringing]
[Milluki] Yes? Oh, hi, Mama! Uh-huh.
[gasps] Yep, I understand.
-[phone beeps]
-Well, Kil, you might wanna know,
those friends of yours are over
at the butlers' quarters.
[cackles] How about it, Kil?
Should I ask Mama
to have the three of them--
[crashing]
[Killua] Milluki...
[echoes] If you so much as touch them,
I'll kill you.
I'm sorry. How rude of me.
I am Killua's mother, you see,
and this is Kalluto.
Why can't Killua come to see us?
Where is he?
In solitary confinement.
Wait, what?
Before he ran away from home,
Killua stabbed his brother, and me.
Yes, that's what he told us.
And then, because he regretted
what he had done,
our Killua returned to us,
and entered solitary confinement,
voluntarily.
In any case, we don't know
when he will choose to leave.
[gasps] What? What is happening?
What are you doing, Father?
Please, don't do anything hasty!
He's only just returned!
-[Milluki] Huh?
-[Zeno] I'm coming in.
ONE KILL A DAY
I believe that'll do for now. Thank you.
But Grandpa Zeno,
he isn't even sorry, not one bit!
[Zeno] Yes, I'm aware of that.
You may go now, Kil.
[Killua] Okay.
[grunts]
-[grunts]
-Huh?
Man, that really hurt.
Hey, Milluki, you're right. I'm not sorry,
but I do feel bad.
That's why I let you slap me around
for a little while.
[Milluki] What was that?
Oh, Kil, Silva would like to see you now.
Dad said that?
Okay, then.
[Milluki grumbles]
Damn it, Grandpa!
Why do you have to go
and spoil him all the time?
That's why he's become such a little punk!
[gasps]
Because Killua is special, Mil.
Tell me, in your opinion,
what do you think of Kil's potential?
-It's incredible, sure.
-Yes, go on.
I think it's safe to say
he's the most talented Zoldyck
in the history of our family, right?
Even Mama thinks so, and I have to agree.
Very good assessments.
But there's just no way he'll ever be
a good assassin. He's way too erratic.
[Zeno] Erratic?
A kid who wants to go and make friends
could never lead the Zoldyck family.
In the end, he's too weak.
Well, mentally, at least.
Hmm...
-[Zeno] Yes, that is true.
-[Milluki] Right? Take me, for example.
I'll kill anyone you want me to,
no questions asked.
Oh, I almost forgot!
My newest bomb is a real winner, Grandpa!
It's tiny enough that I can attach it
to a female mosquito,
and I rigged it to explode
whenever it sucks on a target's blood.
But the problem is that mosquitos
aren't great for precision targeting.
-Mil?
-What?
You're a sharp boy, but that doesn't mean
you're not an idiot, too.
Oh, why must Father be this way?
[sighs]
I'm afraid that something has come up.
Farewell.
Wait! Hold on!
It's just that we'll be staying in town
for a little while.
Please let Killua know.
Yes, very well. I'll be sure to tell him.
Good day.
Who are all of you? Tell me.
We're all friends with Killua.
You're his friends?
[Kikyo] Kalluto! What are you doing?
Come along this instant!
Coming! Sorry, Mother.
It goes without saying,
but these people really creep me out.
And I bet they were lying about
Killua not wanting to see us.
Gon, we can't go back there just yet.
Maybe we should tail those two.
Yeah, but if we go follow them,
I'm worried that it would mean
a whole lot of trouble for her later on.
Yeah. Good point.
I will take you to the butler's quarters.
There is a phone
that connects directly to the mansion.
If Master Zeno answers it, he might...
[grunts]
Who's Master Zeno?
He is Master Killua's grandfather.
[snorting]
So, Kil...
I hear you've made some friends.
[Killua] Yeah.
And what are they like?
"What are they like?"
They're a lot of fun to be with.
I see.
How was the Hunter Exam?
Um, it was easy.
-Sit over here by me, Kil.
-[Killua gasps]
I want to hear all about it.
[gasps]
Your exam experiences,
who you met, how you felt.
You can tell me anything, and everything.
'kay.
[rustling]
I can't believe this.
Father didn't even ask me!
And now, Kil has gone off
to lark about with Papa!
[panting] Unforgivable!
[Killua]
And then, you know what Gon said to him?
He didn't want his legs cut off,
but he didn't want to surrender either!
[both chuckling]
-He's so selfish.
-He's interesting, all right!
And then, Gon's opponent pointed a blade
at his forehead, and that's when Gon--
Kil.
[gasps]
Do you want to see your friends?
No need to hold back. Be honest.
Thinking back... [sighs]
...you and I have never really had
a father-son chat before.
I was raised by my parents
to be an assassin.
And I raised you the same way.
But you and I are different,
and it took you leaving home
for me to realize that.
Oh...
You are indeed my son,
and still, a person all your own.
Live your life.
Remember, you can come home
if you get tired, so...
I'll ask you again.
Do you want to see your friends?
Mm-hm.
Very well.
You're free to go now. But Kil...
Promise me one thing.
That you will never betray your friends.
Got that?
I'll never betray them. I swear.
[Kikyo] Kil? It's too late.
Those three have already left.
Return to your cell.
No way. I'm leaving.
[screams] Kil!
Oh...
Step aside.
[gasps]
[Kikyo chuckling] Oh, Kil.
What a splendid icy glare you have!
[Kikyo] What in the hell were you
thinking? Kil finally came home!
[Silva]
Let the boy do what he wants for now.
You're mad! Listen to yourself!
If Kil is to be head of the family,
this stage is absolutely critical!
So you know what's at stake.
Good. Then stop your griping
and keep your mouth shut!
[cackling] Don't worry,
he'll come back home one day.
After all, he is my son.
[narrator] Killua has been set free,
but Silva confidently declares
that he will return as an assassin.
Meanwhile, Gon and company
head to the butler's quarters.
Whether they will make contact with Killua
remains to be seen.
[theme music plays]
[Gon] Next time.
"Can't See if You're Blind."
Eye for an eye. Eye for a tooth?
[Killua] That's tooth for a tooth!